Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Shashank Chaudhary (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking assignment in Software Development, Web Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Java Microservice Development, Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, AWS, Apache Camel.Rest Web Services.Hibernate



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: Aeris Communications

Current Location: Noida

Pref. Location: Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR, Jaipur

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Web Application Development, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Java Microservice Development, Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security, AWS, Apache

Camel, Rest Web Services, Hibernate

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Having 6years of experience in Java Web Application Development.

Good knowledge on Java 8, Spring Boot, Spring Security, AWS.

Capable of developing Microservices.

Capable of Containerizing the application using Docker containers.

Worked on migration projects from EJB based apps to Microservice.

Can setup a project on one of the build tools Gradle or Maven.

Good knowledge in Jenkins CICD pipeline setup.

Basics of HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Good knowledge on frameworks like Apache Camel, Hibernate.

Expertise in analysing the problem and finding the solution within stipulated time.

Ability to define Testing Scope and Test Strategy for module or project.

An effective communicator with relationship building and excellent interpersonal skills.

Work Experience

Aeris Communications as Senior Software Engineer Sep 2020 to Till Date

Sopra Steria as Senior Software Engineer Oct 2018 to Sep 2020

Java Microservice development

Infosys Ltd as Senior Systems Engineer Dec 2014 to Oct 2018

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Surya World College, PTU in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Java 7, Java 8, React			
Spring, Spring boot, Docker			
Apache Camel, Rest Web Services			
Hibernate			
IBM Rational Application Developer			
Eclipse, STS			
DB2, Oracle			
WebSphere Application Server 8.5			
Tomcat, Weblogic			
MAVEN, GRADLE			
Splunk, Putty			

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time